Shnyar Mohammed

UX/UI Designer | Civil Engineer

With 2 years of experience in UX/UI design, I've played a key role in shaping a SaaS management system and a healthcare app. These projects reflect my dedication to making technology both user-friendly and impactful. It's not just about design; it's about creating digital solutions that matter.

EDUCATION

BSc. in Civil Engineer

University of Sulaymaniyah

2016 - 2020, Sulaymaniyah

EXPERIENCE

Product Designer

Health360

May 2023 - Feb 2024, Baghdad, Remote

Lead the UX and UI designs with the accountability of the design system, I played a pivotal role in designing and building two web applications. Additionally, I contributed to the development of a healthcare app, ensuring a seamless and user-centric experience across these digital platforms.

UI Designer

Charaxwaz app

7-25, Jan 2024, Sulaymaniyah, Hybrid

Contributed to Charaxwaz's success at Smart-Suli Hackathon, winning in the Health Sector during the International Innovation and Entrepreneurship Forum. Played a major role in designing the UI part in 18 days!

UX/UI Designer

Bigayana

Sep 2022 - Nov 2022, Remote Course Project

UX/UI Designer at Bigayna (delivery service) app during bootcamp, leading design efforts and collaborating crossfunctionally for a user-centric app interface. Successfully delivered assets, including wireframes and prototypes, within the bootcamp's timeframe.

Graphic Designer

Health360

May 2023 - Sep 2023, Baghdad, Remote

Produced daily social media posts, business cards, presentations, roller banners, and flyers for Health360, showcasing a comprehensive skill set in graphic design and printed materials.

Passive House Iraq

Nov 2022 - April 2023, Sulaymaniyah, Hybrid

Created social media posts, business cards, and flyers.

Additionally, designed a comprehensive catalogue and company profile for Passive House Iraq, demonstrating a diverse range of design expertise.

Web Content Creator

Passive House Iraq

Feb 2023 - April 2023, Sulaymaniyah, Hybrid

Responsible for updating and creating new content for the Passive House Iraq website, elevated business traffic by updating and creating engaging content for website, contributing to a dynamic online presence.

CERTIFICATION

UX/UI Bootcamp

Re:Coded

June 2022 – Nov 2022, Online

Winner of SmartSuli Hackathon

SmartSuli

7-17-25, Jan 2024, Sulaymaniyah

Business Plan, Branding, and Marketing Strategies Course

Vim Foundation

Dec 2020 - Feb 2021, Sulaymaniyah

Out Standing Excellence Traffic Data Collection

View Pioneer-City LAB Sulaymaniyah

Feb-March 2017 & Jun-Mar 2019, Sulaymaniyah

\(+964 770 677 9432

Portfolio

Industry Knowledge

Product Design

Information Architecture

User Experience

Wireframing

Prototype

User Interface

Interaction Designer

Other skills

Design sprint
Usability testing
A/B testing
User research
User journey mapping
Problem-Solving
SaaS management system
Teamwork
Critical Thinking
Time Management
Business Communications
Agile Product Management
Responsive Designing Skills
Content Strategy
Digital Marketing

Tools

Figma, Notion, Miro, ClickUp, Google Analytics, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, AutoCAD.

Social

ໍາດ linkedin.com/in/shnyar

Languages

Kurdish: Native Proficiency

Arabic: Limited Working Proficiency

English: Full Professional Proficiency